Register of the Boris Bozhnev papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Boris Bozhnev papers
1925-1984
90044
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Papers of the Russian-French poet and artist Boris Bozhnev contain writings, correspondence, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian literature and art and to émigré life in France.
Bozhnev, Boris.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Boris Bozhnev was a Russian poet, artist, and émigré in France.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of material relating to the life and work of the Russian-French poet and artist Boris Bozhnev. It includes writings, correspondence, printed matter, and photographs. The collection also includes a biography of Bozhnev by his wife Ella Kaminer-Bozhnev, her own memoir of their time together, and her correspondence.
Related Collection(s)
Boris Bozhnev papers, 1920-1981, Special Collections, Green Library, Stanford University
Kaminer-Bozhnev, Ella.; Art.; Russian literature.; Russians--France.
- Biographical file, 1935-1983
  - "Ella/Boris, Marseille, Palestine, and Israel, 1939-1947," notebook (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Letters to Ella Kaminer (wife), 1937-1969 (Box-folder 1:2-4)
  - Photographs of Bozhnev and Ella Kaminer, 1935-1969 (Box-folder 1:5)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes photograph of Russian composer Sergei Prokof'ev sighed to Boxhnev, 1923
  - Bozhnev's biography by Ella Kaminer, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 1:6-12)
    Includes notes
  - Clippings on Bozhnev, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Exhibitions of paintings by Bozhnev in France, 1944-1976 (Box-folder 1:14-16, Box-folder 2:1-6)
    Includes correspondence, catalogs, notes, and photocopies of paintings
- Ella Kaminer's correspondence, 1960-1984
  - General, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Bakhrakh, Aleksandr, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Bokov, Nicolas, 1979 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Drozdovsky, Cecile, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Fleĭshman, Lasar, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Henry, Lucien, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - The Institute of Modern Russian Culture, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Kantor, Rachel, 1979 (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Lempert, Iosif Mironovich, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Levin, Mikhail, 1984 (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Library of Congress, 1980 (Box-folder 2:17)
  - Pastor, Gilbert, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Reznikova, Natal'ia Victorovna, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 2:20)
  - Sedykh, Andreĭ, 1980 (Box-folder 2:21)
  - Shakhnivich, Henrik, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Valabrègue, Frederick, 1980 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Yardney, Susanne M., 1979-1982 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Zhaba, Sergeĭ Pavlovich, 1981 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Writings, 1925-1959
  - Bibliography, compiled by Ella Kaminer, 1981 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - "Bor'ba za nesuchshestvovan'e, ", 1925 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - "Bouquet Latent,", 1944 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - "Chetvertyĭ razdel Shopena,", 1952-1959 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - "Chto Del'vig?", 1948 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - "Chtob dol'she sna prodlilos' probuzhden'e,", 1959 (Box-folder 3:9-10, Box-folder 4:1-2)
  - "Elégie,", 1954 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - "Fontan,", 1927 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - "Fuga svetlykh sledov,", 1948 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - "Introduction a L"agrume",", 1935 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - "Izgnanie iz ada,", 1951-1957 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - "Kolchan mufty, zimniĭ akkompaniment,", 1949 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - "Luchezarnaia tvoia,", 1949 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - "Nochnoĭ sneg zametaet sledy Venery,", 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - "Siiaet Bog so svechkoĭ za dushoĭ,", 1950 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - "Tris Préludes d'Hiver,", 1958 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - "Vo khlade sinevy svoeĭ drozhat almazy,", 1951-1957 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - Notes, circa 1950 (Box-folder 4:15)